Everything is interconnected.
كل شيء مترابط
As a Shinnecock Indian, I was raised to know this.
كهندية شينيكوكية، نشأت على تلك القناعة.
We are a small fishing tribe
نحن قبيلة صيد صغيرة
situated on the southeastern tip of Long Island
تحتل الحد الجنوبي الشرقي لـ لونج أيلاند
near the town of Southampton in New York.
قريبا من مدينة ساوثامتون في نيويورك.
When I was a little girl,
عندما كنت بنت صغيرة،
my grandfather took me to sit outside in the sun on a hot summer day.
أخذني جدي للتشمس في يوم شديد الحرارة.
There were no clouds in the sky.
لم تكن هناك سحبا في السماء
And after a while I began to perspire.
وبع\د برهة بدأت أتصبب عرقا.
And he pointed up to the sky, and he said,
بعدها أشار للسماء، وقال،
"Look, do you see that?
"أنظري، هل ترين هذا؟
That's part of you up there.
هذا جزء منك في السماء.
That's your water that helps to make the cloud
هذه مياهك التي تساعد علي تكوين السحب
that becomes the rain that feeds the plants
والذي يصبح مطرا تعيش عليه النباتات
that feeds the animals."
والذي بدوره يكون طعاما للحيوانات."
In my continued exploration of subjects in nature
في رحلة إكتشافي المستمرة للأشياء في الطبيعة
that have the ability to illustrate the interconnection of all life,
والتي لديها المقدرة على رسم العلاقات الترابطية بين أجزاء الحياة
I started storm chasing in 2008
بدأت في ملاحقة العواصف في عام 2008
after my daughter said, "Mom, you should do that."
بعد أن قالت ابنتي،"أمي، يجب أن تقومي بذلك."
And so three days later, driving very fast,
وبعد ثلاثة أيام، أقود سيارتي بسرعة،
I found myself stalking a single type of giant cloud called the super cell,
وجدت نفسي متعقبة أثر نوع عملاق من العواصف يلقب بالخلية الخارقة
capable of producing grapefruit-size hail
قادرة على تكوين بردا في حجم ثمرة الجريب فروت
and spectacular tornadoes,
وأعاصير مذهلة،
although only two percent actually do.
بالرغم من أن 2% فقط منها
These clouds can grow so big, up to 50 miles wide
تستطيع أن تبلغ حجما هائلا، يصل لـ50 ميلا في الإتساع
and reach up to 65,000 feet into the atmosphere.
وتصل لإرتفاع 65,000 قدم فوق سطح البحر.
They can grow so big, blocking all daylight,
تستطيع بلوغ هذا الحجم، وحجب ضوء النهار،
making it very dark and ominous standing under them.
وتحوله لظلام وتجعل الموقف أسفلها لا يحمد عقباه.
Storm chasing is a very tactile experience.
تعقب العاصفة خبرة ملموسة جدا.
There's a warm, moist wind blowing at your back
هناك ريح رطبة دافئة تعصف من خلفك
and the smell of the earth, the wheat, the grass, the charged particles.
ورائحة الأرض، والقمح، والحشائش والجزيئات المشحونة.
And then there are the colors in the clouds
وبعدها هناك الألوان في السحب
of hail forming, the greens and the turquoise blues.
الناتجة عن تشكل البرد درجات الأخضر والأزرق التركوازي.
I've learned to respect the lightning.
تعلمت أن أحترم الرعد.
My hair used to be straight.
بأن أُوقف له شعر رأسي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I'm just kidding.
أنا أمزح فقط.
What really excites me about these storms
الذي يثيرني في تلك العواصف
is their movement, the way they swirl and spin and undulate,
هي حركتها، الطريقة التي تتكون وتدور وتتموج بها
with their lava lamp-like mammatus clouds.
وبالسحب الصدرية الشبيهة بالحمم البركانية
They become lovely monsters.
وتتحول لوحوش جميلة.
When I'm photographing them,
عندما ألتقط صورهم
I cannot help but remember my grandfather's lesson.
لا أستطيع إلا تذكر كلمة جدي.
As I stand under them,
وأنا أقف أسفل منهم،
I see not just a cloud,
لا أرى مجرد سحابة،
but understand that what I have the privilege to witness
ولكن أكون متفهمة أني لدي الشرف لأشهد
is the same forces, the same process in a small-scale version
نفس القوى، ونفس العملية على مستوى مصغر
that helped to create our galaxy, our solar system, our sun
والتي ساعدت على نشأة مجرتنا، ونظامنا الشمسي، وشمسنا
and even this very planet.
وحتى هذا الكوكب.
All my relations. Thank you.
وكل علاقاتي. أشكركم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)